Have you ever wondered why your brother or sister doesn’t look exactly like you despite having the same family tree?
你有没有想过，为什么你和兄弟姐妹有着相同的家族谱系，长相却不完全一样？
If you think that’s odd, even stranger is the idea that you and your sibling may have very different ancestry genes.
如果你觉得这件事很奇怪，那更不可思议的是，你和兄弟姐妹可能携带差异很大的祖先基因。
You have the same parents, and therefore the exact same ancestors, but somehow your DNA tests come back with very different results.
你们有着相同的父母，自然也有着完全相同的先祖，但DNA检测结果却莫名其妙地大相径庭。
How is this even possible?
这究竟是怎么回事呢？
Children inherit half of their DNA from each parent, via the sperm from the father and the egg from the mother.
孩子会从父母双方各继承一半的DNA，分别来自父亲的精子和母亲的卵子。
Our bodies contain 46 chromosomes, or 23 pairs.
人体含有46条染色体，也就是23对。
However, each reproductive cell has only 23 individual chromosomes.
但每个生殖细胞只含有23条独立的染色体。
When the bodies of our forbearers created their sex cells, the cells engaged in genetic reshuffling, meaning each of the 23 chromosomes is a unique combination of an original pair.
当我们祖先的身体产生生殖细胞时，这些细胞会发生基因重组，也就是说这23条染色体中的每一条，都是其原始染色体对的独特组合。
This process is also called genetic recombination.
这个过程也被称为遗传重组。
This is why Dr. Prosanta Chakrabarty, a scientist who studies fish to help explain the evolution of human beings and our planet, says that your sister could be 10% more "French" than you, despite having the same primogenitors.
正因如此，通过研究鱼类来解释人类及地球进化历程的科学家普洛桑塔·查克拉巴蒂博士表示，即便拥有相同的直系祖先，你的姐妹也可能比你多10%的“法国血统”。
And the further you go back in your lineage, the more confusing it can be.
而且追溯的谱系年代越久远，情况可能就越复杂。
You inherit 25% of each grandparent's DNA.
你会从每位祖父母那里继承25%的DNA。
However, this process of recombination means that inevitably some of their genetic make-up will be lost along the way.
但遗传重组的过程意味着，他们的部分基因构成必然会在遗传过程中丢失。
This could mean that the genes you inherited from your grandparent, could be completely different to those your cousin received.
这就可能导致你从祖父母那里继承的基因，和你的表亲所继承的基因完全不同。
Those studying genealogy should also be aware that modern DNA testing might not give you an accurate idea of your ancestry as it is tested against a current, but incomplete database.
研究家谱学的人还应当注意，现代DNA检测或许无法准确呈现你的先祖谱系，因为检测所参照的数据库虽然是最新的，但并不完整。
Many of the genetic samples come from North America and Western Europe. The genes passed down from your ancestors is sampled and matched with people who originated from a certain area.
许多基因样本都来自北美和西欧，检测时会将你祖先传下来的基因取样，与特定地区起源人群的基因进行比对。
However, without enough samples from the Middle East or Africa, the results may be inaccurate.
但由于缺乏来自中东或非洲的足够样本，检测结果可能存在偏差。
Dr. Prosanta Chakrabarty says that only 1% of our genetic make-up is unique to us, and that it is an incomplete mash-up of our ancestors’.
普洛桑塔·查克拉巴蒂博士称，我们的基因构成中只有1%是独属于自己的，其余都是祖先基因的不完全混合体。
So, the next time someone says you look a bit like you're from a certain country, you may well be. But it might not show up in your tests.
所以下次再有人说你看起来像某个国家的人时，这种感觉很可能是对的，但这一点或许不会在你的DNA检测结果中体现出来。